<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hello {code} blog</title>
    <link>https://hellocodeblog.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on hello {code} blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2019 by Philipp Badenhoop. All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 18:52:04 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hellocodeblog.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://hellocodeblog.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellocodeblog.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a german computer science student who just wants to share his own personal projects, ideas and thoughts on the web. My main interests are in robotics and artificial intelligence.
Philipp Badenhoop</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://hellocodeblog.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 18:52:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellocodeblog.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>Feel free to send me a message by filling out the form below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to asionet</title>
      <link>https://hellocodeblog.com/post/asionet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellocodeblog.com/post/asionet/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In case you&amp;rsquo;ve ever done some network programming in C++, you probably stumbled upon the quasi-standard boost::asio library. It uses asynchronous programming making it scalable but on the other side, it takes quite some time to learn how to use it correctly.
asionet is built on top of boost::asio which makes it 100% compatible with it but easier to use at the same time. For example, managing timeouts and sending and receiving serialized messages is done with only a few lines of code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cookie</title>
      <link>https://hellocodeblog.com/cookie-preferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellocodeblog.com/cookie-preferences/</guid>
      <description>Cookie Preferences Cookies are very small text files that are stored on your computer when you visit a website. We use cookies to analyze our website traffic. For more information on cookie usage on our website, please read our privacy policy.
You can change your preferences and decline certain types of cookies to be stored on your computer while browsing our website. You can also remove any cookies already stored on your computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://hellocodeblog.com/privacy-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 18:52:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hellocodeblog.com/privacy-policy/</guid>
      <description>Privacy Policy Effective date: December 29, 2018
hellocodeblog (&amp;ldquo;us&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;our&amp;rdquo;) operates the https://hellocodeblog.com website (the &amp;ldquo;Service&amp;rdquo;).
This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you use our Service and the choices you have associated with that data. Our Privacy Policy for hellocodeblog is based on the Free Privacy Policy Template Website.
We use your data to provide and improve the Service.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>